{"Topic": "Mughal Rule", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Which Mughal ruler earned the title Insan-i-kamil (Perfect Man) for his peaceful personality and patience?", "op1": "Shahjahan", "op2": "Humayun", "op3": "Jahangir", "op4": "Akbar", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which among the following books was authored by a lady of the Mughal Royal House?", "op1": "Babar Namah", "op2": "Akbar Namah", "op3": "Humayun Namah", "op4": "Badshah Namah", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "At which of the following battles was Humayun defeated by Sher Shar Suri?", "op1": "Battle of Chausa", "op2": "Battle of Khanwa", "op3": "First Battle of Panipat", "op4": "Battle of Thanesar", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Where did Babar die?", "op1": "Agra", "op2": "Kabul", "op3": "Lahore", "op4": "Delhi", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following statements about Humayun is/are correct?", "op1": "1 only", "op2": "2 only", "op3": "Both 1 and 2", "op4": "Neither 1 nor 2", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "ect the correct answer using the code given below:", "op1": "Babar", "op2": "Akbar", "op3": "Jahangir", "op4": "Shahjahan", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "e:", "op1": "Mahananda Pande", "op2": "Lal Kalawant", "op3": "Baz Bahadur", "op4": "Ramtanu Pande", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which Mughal Emperor prohibited the use of tobacco?", "op1": "Jahangir", "op2": "Shahjahan", "op3": "Akbar", "op4": "Aurangzeb", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which one of the following was the original name of Tansen, the famous musician in the court of Akbar?", "op1": "Akbar", "op2": "Aurangzeb", "op3": "Jahangir", "op4": "Shah Jahan", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who among the following was illiterate?", "op1": "Paddy crop", "op2": "Cash crop", "op3": "Coarse crop", "op4": "Crop grown in the arid zone", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Painting reached its highest level of development during the reign of", "op1": "Akbar", "op2": "Jahangir", "op3": "Shah Jahan", "op4": "Aurangzeb", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which one among the following depicts the correct meaning of the term Jins-i-kamil concerning crops in Mughal India?", "op1": "Aurangzeb", "op2": "Akbar", "op3": "Shah Jahan", "op4": "Bahadur Shah Zafar", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "With whose permission did the English set up their first factory in Surat?", "op1": "1 - b; 2 - d; 3 - a; 4 - c", "op2": "1 - b; 2 - a; 3 - d; 4 - c", "op3": "1 - c; 2 - d; 3 - a; 4 - b", "op4": "1 - b; 2 - c; 3 - a; 4 - d", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The city of Prayag was named Allahabad, the city of Allah by", "op1": "Balban", "op2": "Qutubuddin Aibak", "op3": "Timur", "op4": "Alauddin Khilji", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Match the original names of Mughal rulers with their popular names:", "op1": "Rana Sangha of Mewar", "op2": "Rana Pratap of Mewar", "op3": "Ibrahim Lodhi", "op4": "Daulat Khan Lodhi", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "To which of the following was Babar related on his father's side?", "op1": "Dara Shikoh", "op2": "Aurangzeb", "op3": "Shuja", "op4": "Murad Baksh", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Whom did Babar defeat in the Battle of Khanua in 1527?", "op1": "Aurangzeb", "op2": "Akbar", "op3": "Babar", "op4": "Bahadur Shah", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Whom did Shah Jahan appoint as the Governor of Mughal provinces in the Deccan?", "op1": "1 - b; 2 - d; 3 - a; 4 - c", "op2": "1 - b; 2 - d; 3 - c; 4 - a", "op3": "1 - b; 2 - c; 3 - d; 4 - a", "op4": "1 - a; 2 - c; 3 - d; 4 - b", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which Mughal emperor assumed the title of Alamgir?", "op1": "Arabic", "op2": "Turki", "op3": "Persian", "op4": "Urdu", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Match the battles during Mughal rule with their years:", "op1": "Raja Man Singh", "op2": "Birbal", "op3": "Faizi", "op4": "Todar Mal", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "In which language did Babar write his autobiography Tuzuk-i-babari?", "op1": "Berar", "op2": "Mewar", "op3": "Gujarat", "op4": "Bengal", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who of the following was the revenue minister of Akbar?"}, {"Question": "Who of the following was the author of Badshah Nama?", "op1": "Inayat Khan", "op2": "Abdul Hamid Lahori", "op3": "Gulbadan Begum", "op4": "Abul Fazl", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following Mughal rulers built the Shalimar Bagh at Srinagar?", "op1": "Akbar", "op2": "Shah Jahan", "op3": "Aurangzeb", "op4": "Jahangir", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following Mughal monuments is not made of marble?", "op1": "Moti Masjid", "op2": "Humayun's Tomb", "op3": "Tomb of Idmat-ud-daula", "op4": "Taj Mahal", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "To whom is the Bibi ka Maqbara, a monument built by Azam Shah, son of Aurangzeb at Aurangabad dedicated?", "op1": "Jodha Bai", "op2": "Mumtaz Begum", "op3": "Rabia Durrani (Dilras Banu Begum)", "op4": "Chand Bibi", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "During the reign of which Mughal emperor, was the empire territorially most extensive?", "op1": "Akbar", "op2": "Shah Jahan", "op3": "Jahangir", "op4": "Aurangzeb", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following was the biggest port during the Mughal period?", "op1": "Hoogly", "op2": "Chittagong", "op3": "Balasore", "op4": "Surat", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following described Taj Mahal as \"A teardrop on the cheek of eternity\"?", "op1": "Jawaharlal Nehru", "op2": "Rabindranath Tagore", "op3": "George Bernard Shaw", "op4": "Richard Attenburrough", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who led the Mughal forces at the Battle of Haldighati against Rana Pratap of Mewar?", "op1": "Raja Man Singh", "op2": "Bairam Khan", "op3": "Todar Mal", "op4": "Prince Salim", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following Rajput dynasties did not surrender to Akbar?", "op1": "Parmar", "op2": "Pratihara", "op3": "Rathor", "op4": "Sisodia", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following introduced the policy of Sulh-i-kul?", "op1": "Aurangzeb", "op2": "Akbar", "op3": "Humayun", "op4": "Shahjahan", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The Mansabdari system introduced by Akbar, was borrowed from the system in -", "op1": "Turkey", "op2": "Persia", "op3": "Afghanistan", "op4": "Mongolia", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following was the last Mughal emperor to sit on the peacock throne?", "op1": "Aurangzeb", "op2": "Mohammad Shah", "op3": "Shah Alam II", "op4": "Alamgir II", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who were the ahdis of Akbar's time?", "op1": "Village level money-lenders", "op2": "Village guards", "op3": "Cashiers working in diwani", "op4": "Foot-soldiers in the army", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Dara Shikoh finally lost the war of succession to Aurangzeb in the battle of", "op1": "Dharmat", "op2": "Samugarh", "op3": "Deorai", "op4": "Khanua", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The innovator of the Revenue settlement during the rule of Akbar was", "op1": "Raja Mansingh", "op2": "Raja Bhagwan Das", "op3": "Raja Todarmal", "op4": "Raja Birbal", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who, among the following great Mughals, was also a first-rate poet?", "op1": "Akbar", "op2": "Babur", "op3": "Jahangir", "op4": "Shah Jahan", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which styles of sculpture are found in Mughal Art?", "op1": "Sino-Indian", "op2": "Indo-European", "op3": "Indo-Persian", "op4": "Indo-Greek", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The Mughal emperor who wrote his autobiography was :", "op1": "Akbar", "op2": "Shahjahan", "op3": "Humayun", "op4": "Babar", "Answer": 3}]}